<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>DF Blogs</title>
    <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com" />
    <updated>2022-08-27T09:39:23+03:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>thefourCraft</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Log4j Killed Me</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/log4j-killed-me/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/log4j-killed-me/index.html</id>
            <category term="Servers"/>
            <category term="Security"/>
            <category term="IMS - Network"/>

        <updated>2022-08-27T09:39:23+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    What is log4shell? The Log4Shell problem is a security problem that was discovered in Java software. The problem affects servers in the world around the world. Since December 10, 2021, days after industry experts discovered the Log4Shell flaw in servers supporting the Minecraft game. According&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>What is log4shell?</h2>
<p>The Log4Shell problem is a security problem that was discovered in Java software. <br>The problem affects servers in the world around the world. <br>Since December 10, 2021, days after industry experts discovered the Log4Shell flaw in servers supporting the Minecraft game.<br><br>According to one team tracking the impact.<br>The vulnerability is a potential threat to millions of other applications and devices worldwide.<br><br>In the days following the announcement of the vulnerability, Check Point tracked millions of attacks initiated by people, with some research studies at a rate of over a hundred attacks per minute, which ultimately resulted in over 40% of the world's business networks being attacked.<br><br>Cloudflare CEO Matthew Prince says evidence of use or apparent testing of the vulnerability was seen as early as December 1, nine days before the vulnerability was publicly disclosed.</p>
<h3>Why We Closed Our Minecraft Servers Immediately?</h3>
<p>Our security system and some functions in the Minecraft game were at risk from abuse and damage to our quality and security capabilities.<br>Minecraft is the source where the vulnerability was discovered.</p>
<h3>The Aftermath</h3>
<p>We had to update and change a lot of the source code for our in-game security system<br>and manually update 100k files to meet the new security system configurations.<br>while some of the poses were automatic we still had to do a lot of work by hand<br>also, all other plugins and servers had to be updated to the new server software that has been released to fix log4shell</p>
<h3>Long Days</h3>
<p>me and our small server team, worked around the clock for a week to fix the issue on all servers and update over 200K lines of code, 200+ plugins, and over 500K configuration files.<br>This is not even counting the sheer number of hours spent on testing the security of the new system and figuring out different compatibility issues.<br>As a mature DevOps engineer, it was kind of my first major skill check.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>.ml Failure</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/nl-failure/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/nl-failure/index.html</id>
            <category term="Security"/>
            <category term="Network"/>
            <category term="IMS - Network"/>
            <category term="Cloudflare"/>

        <updated>2022-08-27T09:24:19+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    What Is A .ml domain? The domain(.ml) was initially managed by Sotelma, a Malian telecommunications company. After Selma was privatized in 2009, the .ml zone was redelegated by IANA to the Agence des Technologies de l’Information et de la Communication (AGETIC), a Malian government agency,&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>What Is A .ml domain?</h2>
<p>The domain(.ml) was initially managed by Sotelma, a Malian telecommunications company.<br>After Selma was privatized in 2009, the .ml zone was redelegated by IANA to the Agence des Technologies de l’Information et de la Communication (AGETIC), a Malian government agency, and the process was completed in 2013.<br><br>The agency then announced that it would give away <i>.ml</i> domains for free with a view to improving the usage and knowledge of the IT industry in Mali. <br>It is the first African nation to start giving away domains for free.<br><br>However, people outside of Africa and registry companies took advantage of this and started offering free domains.<sup id="cite_ref-4" class="reference"></sup></p>
<h2>Why Using A Free Domain Bad?</h2>
<p>free domains are not granted that you will keep them, because the domains are free you often find them unsafe and unreliable.</p>
<h3>Freenom | Stay Away From It</h3>
<p>With Freenom offering free domains to help people enter the online world with ease, an obvious question arises about its safety. If you are also curious to know whether is Freenom safe or not, I’d like to share that <strong>it is not safe and involves a lot of risks</strong>.</p>
<p>The foremost risk factor involved in getting a free domain from Freenom is the termination of your domain at any moment. This leads to a waste of all your time and efforts spent on the free domain.</p>
<p>In my web development journey, I’ve seen many horror stories of people who blindly believed this free domain gimmick of Freenom, only to be surprised later with their domain/account terminated.</p>
<p>So I’ve researched deeply about this free offering from Freenom to bring a detailed review of its services. Hopefully, this article will help you know what to expect in advance when you are about to use a Freenom domain.</p>
<p>In this article, I address all the safety aspects of a Freenom domain, the legality of Freenom, and any hidden costs involved when taking up a free domain. You will get to know how the company makes money without charging you for the domain.</p>
<h2><span id="Is_Freenom_safe">Is Freenom Safe?</span></h2>
<p>To put it shortly <strong>NO. <br></strong>The safety of a free domain from Freenom is truly questionable. <br>In my opinion, the domain that you register with Freenom is not safe at all since you are not the owner of the domain. <br>The <strong>company owns your domain and has complete control over it.</strong></p>
<p>You are always at the risk of losing all the resources and time that you invested into the website, without any prior warning since <strong>Freenom owns your domain and can take it over whenever it wants</strong>. <br>And with <strong>no legal rights to your domain</strong>, you will be left with no option to claim it.</p>
<p><strong>Freenom </strong>also has an automatic traffic analyzer that observes traffic flow at the domains it registers. <br><strong>The company can cancel your domain name if it is not getting any traffic</strong> over some time.</p>
<p>On the other hand, when your domain starts receiving a good amount of traffic, the company might mark your domain as “<strong>Fraud</strong>” and <strong>steal it from you</strong>. <br>It can redirect your website users to another page filled with online advertisements all over.</p>
<p>You will be surprised to know that even the paid domains registered with Freenom are also unreliable.<br>The company resells your domain to the person paying extra money.</p>
<h2><span id="Is_Freenom_legit_legally">Is Freenom Legit Legally?</span></h2>
<p>Freenom is a fraud company in the manner it conducts its domain registration business.</p>
<p>You will be surprised to know that Freenom had its <strong>ICANN registrar accreditation suspended in 2015 for cybersquatting</strong> rival companies. <br>The suspension was, however, later lifted.</p>
<p>That being said, the company is now backed by Kima Ventures, a reputed French venture capital firm.<br>So, for now, it is in safe hands and can be trusted a little for the time being.</p>
<h2><span id="Best_Alternative_to_Freenom">Best Alternative To Freenom</span></h2>
<p>Cloudflare is your best choice.<br>Securely register new domains, transfer existing domains, and effortlessly consolidate and manage all your domain portfolios, with transparent, no-markup pricing. <br>Eliminate surprise renewal fees and hidden add-on charges.</p>
<p>Cloudflare Registrar supports common top-level domains (TLDs) including .com, .net, .org, as well as hundreds more.</p>
<h5>Custom Domain Protection with Cloudflare</h5>
<p>Custom Domain Protection, a Cloudflare Registrar feature available on the Enterprise Plan, is the highest level of registrar security.<br>It protects your organization from domain hijacking with high-touch, on, and offline verification of any changes to your Registrar account. <br>Cloudflare is an ICANN accredited registrar providing secure domain registration for high-profile domains.</p>
<h2>What Happened To isrealmincraft.ml</h2>
<p>When we just got started with servers and managing we used a domain name from Freenom which was taken away from us, because of "fraud".<br>at first, I didn't catch the issue and didn't understand why people can't connect to our server, after talking with Cloudflare's support we made to the conclusion that Freenom caused all the problems.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/e7ef83_b4f70a1c2a6d4d55bdc2a42d8b3727eb~mv2.jpg/v1/fill/w_740,h_400,al_c,q_80,usm_0.66_1.00_0.01,enc_auto/e7ef83_b4f70a1c2a6d4d55bdc2a42d8b3727eb~mv2.jpg" data-is-external-image="true" ></p>
<h4 class="align-center"><strong>DON'T REGISTER FREE DOMAINS, IT'S NOT WORTH THE RISK</strong></h4>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>IMS Double Net Bug</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/ims-double-net-bug/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/ims-double-net-bug/index.html</id>
            <category term="Tips &amp; Tricks"/>
            <category term="Servers"/>
            <category term="Router"/>
            <category term="Network"/>
            <category term="ISP"/>
            <category term="IMS - Network"/>

        <updated>2022-08-27T00:52:46+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    IMS - Network, is an Israeli gaming community that builds and develops game servers for free. Double NAT occurs when you connect your router to an ISP gateway or another router. Because NAT is performed by each router or gateway, your network is split into&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <p>IMS - Network, is an Israeli gaming community that builds and develops game servers for free.  </p>
<h2>What is a double net? </h2>
<p><span class="ng-emphasis">Double NAT</span> occurs when you connect your router to an ISP gateway or another router. Because NAT is performed by each router or gateway, your network is split into two different private networks. <br>The devices connected to one private network might have communication problems with the devices connected to the other private network.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//Blog-IMG.png" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-xs.png 300w ,https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-sm.png 480w ,https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-md.png 768w ,https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-lg.png 1024w ,https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-xl.png 1360w ,https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/6//responsive/Blog-IMG-2xl.png 1600w"  alt="Double Net Demo" width="1920" height="683"></figure>
<p>As you can see in the illustration I have created an example for a double net issue.<br>The double net accounts between the routers, the main problem that you will experience will use port forwarding and triggering to not work.<br>which is a major problem... if you need to open a port... because you are running a server that players need to access. </p>
<h3>How to Identify a double net issue?</h3>
<p>Look for 4 simple problems that can occur with a double net network:</p>
<ul>
<li>Online games</li>
<li>VPN connections</li>
<li>Port forwarding and triggering</li>
<li>Secure websites that use SSL</li>
</ul>
<h3>How To Fix double net problems?</h3>
<p>If your router is connected to an Internet service provider (ISP) gateway or another router, and you are having network problems, your network might be set up to perform double network address translation (NAT).</p>
<p class="msg msg--warning"><strong>Note: </strong>If you connected another router to your ISP gateway or main router to improve WiFi coverage or add more LAN ports to your home network, you might want to consider other solutions.<br>If you have a particular area where you want to improve WiFi coverage, a WiFi extender is a better choice.<br>If you want to improve WiFi coverage throughout your entire home, a mesh WiFi system is ideal.<br>If you simply want to add more LAN ports to your existing router, an affordable unmanaged Ethernet switch is appropriate.</p>
<p>There are multiple ways to fix double NAT issues with your network. <br>Your options depend on whether your router.</p>
<p class="msg msg--info"><strong>Suggestion: </strong>Because all routers and ISP are different, I would recommend contacting your ISP and coordinating with their support team if you don't know what you are doing.</p>
<h4>Most Common Way To Fix Double NET issues</h4>
<p>If your router is connected to another router, you can resolve double NAT issues by removing the first router from your network, putting the first router in bridge mode, <br>or putting your router in access point (AP) mode.</p>
<p>I recommend that you remove the first router for the best network performance.<br>If you can’t remove the first router, check its capabilities to see if it supports bridge mode. <br>Most routers support bridge mode, but routers from other brands might not. <br>If you can’t remove or put the first router in bridge mode, you must put your main router in AP(access point) mode.</p>
<p class="msg msg--highlight "><strong>Note:</strong> Some router features are disabled in AP mode.</p>
<h3>What Happened on IMS - Network's server infrastructure?</h3>
<p>As all humans, we make mistakes that can cause problems or even break critical systems and operations... <br>While Building an exception for our existing server room we used a router that was donated to us by a player on our server... <br>After deploying the router nothing stood out of the ordinary<br>One day we had extra traffic of players on the server so our management application deployed extra Minecraft server instances.<br>Unfortunately, the ports failed to connect because we created a double net, which caused the existing server to overload with players and lag, and in our industry, you can't afford lags on your server.<br>We do have primitive figures and our team was immediately alerted but, the investigation into identifying the problem took us 2 weeks.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Nail Beta Testing</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/nail-beta-testing/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/nail-beta-testing/index.html</id>
            <category term="Tips &amp; Tricks"/>

        <updated>2022-08-21T23:53:03+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/5/Beta.png" alt="Beta Testing Blog Image" />
                    Beta tests are important for companies and they are benefiting everyone who is involved. Companies that run beta tests are genuinely interested in hearing your feedback and what you think. If you’re selected as a beta tester, you need to make the most of the&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/5/Beta.png" alt="Beta Testing Blog Image" />
                <p>Beta tests are important for companies and they are benefiting everyone who is involved.<br>Companies that run beta tests are genuinely interested in hearing your feedback and what you think. <br>If you’re selected as a beta tester, you need to make the most of the opportunity. <br>Share every thought, note every bug, and get engaged in the process.<br><br>The more active you are on the project, the more likely you will be to earn any project incentive and get other chances to test with the company.<br>If the company likes you they will contact you again and maybe even give you benefits! </p>
<h2>Let's Learn Some Tips To Nail Beta Testing </h2>
<p class="dropcap">1. <strong>Don't OverWork Your Self<br></strong>Spend a little time every day doing something on every part of the product. Budget sometime each day to submit feedback.  By doing a little bit every day you will test the product in its entirety, have great performance numbers, and have a lot of fun Because getting access to beta testing usually means new features and improvements, also remember you are #first.<strong><br></strong></p>
<p class="dropcap">2.<strong>Communicate<br></strong>Be communicative and responsive throughout the project. Remember that the people running the test are eager to hear what you have to say and what you’re experiencing. It’s incredibly important to monitor your bugs, watch the forums, and respond quickly to any inquiries the beta team might have for more information. Being Active and also providing human interest can go a long way.<strong><br></strong></p>
<p class="dropcap">3. <strong>Be Clear and Thorough</strong><br>Make your communication clear and detailed. Your feedback needs to give the beta team a solid understanding of your issues, ideas, and opinions. If they don’t understand what you’re saying or don’t have enough data, they might have to come back to you again, which just takes up more of everyone’s time. They need to be able to understand your comments and act on them immediately. Screenshots and pictures often help. Also writing the issue and using the right words is important, I often use emojis to describe sections and titles. </p>
<p class="dropcap">4.<strong>Privacy as Always </strong><br>Many companies spend months designing and building their test product. They are spending many thousands of dollars to prepare for its launch. If the beta test is private, it’s your responsibility and obligation to keep everything about the beta test secret. Don’t blog, don’t Tweet, don’t chat, don’t post anything anywhere about the beta test. Don’t even mention you are involved in the project. Remember, these companies are trusting you with their new product. In return, you should show them respect by keeping everything you experience a secret. Also, you can get sued, because companies sometimes sign you up with an argument when joining the beta test.</p>
<p class="dropcap">5. <strong>Relax</strong><br>Be flexible and understanding. Product development is a complicated process that involves many people and many tasks. Your role in this process is to share your perspective regarding the product. If the company discovers an important issue or needs to change the direction of the project, that could change the schedule. They might need to extend the test or cut it short to meet their new schedule. These changes are commonplace in beta, so please be willing to adapt to them. At the end of the day, you are just tasked to help beta test the product. </p>
<h3>About Me</h3>
<p>I love beta testing, getting access to tools/products before everyone is a huge key to getting an upper age on the market. <br>Most importantly the benefits that you are getting are knowledge and new people that you can meet and collaborate with in the future.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>How Does a ZTNA Work</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/how-does-a-ztna-work/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/how-does-a-ztna-work/index.html</id>
            <category term="Zero Trust"/>

        <updated>2022-08-21T20:31:47+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/4/ZTNA.png" alt="ZTNA Blog Post Cover Image" />
                    While the specific tools used to implement Zero Trust Architecture may vary Implementing a Zero Trust Architecture project calls out some key functions: So, you are ready to create your zero-trust network? Implementing zero trust principles within an organization’s environment requires the development of a&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/4/ZTNA.png" alt="ZTNA Blog Post Cover Image" />
                <p>While the specific tools used to implement Zero Trust Architecture may vary<br>Implementing a Zero Trust Architecture project calls out some key functions:</p>
<ul class="learning-list">
<li><strong>Application vs. network access:</strong> <br>ZTNA treats application access separately from network access. Connecting to a network does not automatically grant a user the right to access an application.</li>
<li><strong>Hidden IP addresses:</strong> <br>ZTNA does not expose IP addresses to the network. The rest of the network remains invisible to connected devices, except for the application or service they are connected to.</li>
<li><strong>Device security:</strong> </li>
<li>ZTNA can incorporate the risk and security posture of devices as factors in access decisions. It does this by running software on the device itself (see "Agent-based ZTNA vs. service-based ZTNA" below) or by analyzing network traffic to and from the device.</li>
<li><strong>Additional factors:</strong> </li>
<li>Unlike traditional access control, which only grants access based on user identity and role, ZTNA can evaluate risks associated with additional factors like user location, timing, and frequency of requests, the apps and data being requested, and more. A user could sign in to a network or application, but if their device is not trusted, access is denied.</li>
<li><strong>No MPLS:</strong> <br>ZTNA uses encrypted Internet connections over TLS instead of MPLS-based WAN connections. Traditional corporate networks are built on private MPLS connections. ZTNA is built on the public Internet instead, using TLS encryption to keep network traffic private. ZTNA sets up small encrypted tunnels between a user and an application, as opposed to connecting a user to a larger network.</li>
<li><strong>IdP and SSO:</strong> <br>Most ZTNA solutions integrate with separate identity providers (IdPs), single sign-on (SSO) platforms, or both. SSO allows users to authenticate identity for all applications; the IdP stores user identity and determines associated user privileges.</li>
<li><strong>Agent vs. service:</strong> <br>ZTNA can either use an endpoint agent or be based in the cloud. The difference is explained below.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Explaining the Zero Trust Framework</h2>
<p>So, you are ready to create your zero-trust network?<br>Implementing zero trust principles within an organization’s environment requires the development of a zero trust network. <br>A zero-trust network implements and enforces zero trust policies, such as zero-trust network access (ZTNA) or Software Defined Perimeter (SDP), <br>consistently across an organization’s entire environment.<br><br>In this blog post, I prepared some tips to know if you really need ZTNA for this app</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Zero Trust vs VPN</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/zero-trust-vs-vpn/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/zero-trust-vs-vpn/index.html</id>
            <category term="Zero Trust"/>
            <category term="Cloudflare"/>

        <updated>2022-08-20T21:35:49+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/3/VPN-VS-ZN.png" alt="Zero Trust vs VPN Image" />
                    VPN is what many organizations use to control access instead of ZTNA. Once users are logged in to a VPN, they gain access to the entire network and all the resources on that network (this is often called the castle-and-moat model). ZTNA instead only grants&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/media/posts/3/VPN-VS-ZN.png" alt="Zero Trust vs VPN Image" />
                <p>VPN is what many organizations use to control access instead of ZTNA. <br>Once users are logged in to a VPN, they gain access to the entire network and all the resources on that network (this is often called the castle-and-moat model). ZTNA instead only grants access to the specific application requested and denies access to applications and data by default.<br><br></p>
<p>One of the biggest threats to network security is a company’s own Virtual Private Network (VPN). <br>Based on old network architectures, VPN’s assumption of a securely fixed perimeter surrounding a trusted network is a dated design pattern that undermines security. <br>Zero Trust is a framework of security concepts that are better suited to the way business works today.</p>
<h2 id="what-is-zero-trust" class="sc-ghizgr-0 DIklJ">What is Zero Trust?</h2>
<p>You Can read about it on my main website, and see my demo of a zero-trust system implantation</p>
<h2 id="why-is-zero-trust-a-superior-solution-to-vpns" class="sc-ghizgr-0 DIklJ">Why Zero Trust is Better?</h2>
<p>VPNs are the traditional choice for secure remote access because they work well with legacy perimeter-based security models. <br>However, they have several limitations that make them ill-suited to the security needs of the modern enterprise</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Perimeter-Focused Security:</strong> <br>VPN helps reinforce the traditional perimeter-based security model because an authenticated user is granted full access to the corporate network. This allows an attacker to move laterally through the corporate network after gaining access via compromised VPN credentials or exploitation of a VPN vulnerability.</li>
<li><strong>Network-Level Access Controls:</strong> <br>VPNs implement access controls at the network level without visibility into or control over the application layer. This provides overly-permissive access to users, granting read, write, and execute access to resources within different applications.</li>
<li><strong>No Cloud Support:</strong> <br>VPNs are typically designed to provide secure remote access to the corporate network. Often, they have limited support for cloud-based resources located outside of the traditional perimeter.</li>
<li><strong>Poor Support for BYOD Devices:</strong> <br>Allowing BYOD devices to access the corporate VPN provides access to corporate resources from unmanaged, non-corporate endpoints. This may allow malware or other cyber threats direct access to the corporate network.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Why ZTNA Is The Future?</h2>
<p>With a zero trust security strategy, VPNs are no longer a viable secure remote access solution. ZTNA offers an alternative with several benefits when compared to VPNs</p>
<p>Implementing zero trust technologies with careful planning will make the cloud a more manageable place for any organization. <br><br>The use of ZTNA, IAM, and MFA can prevent unwanted events from occurring. <br>New compute instances or storage buckets cannot just “pop up” like weeds in unpredictable locations. Zero trust will cultivate them into domesticated plants confined to well-defined flowerpots.</p>
<p>These flowerpots are your micro-perimeters, which you can isolate using micro-segmentation. <br><br>They will enable easier monitoring and tighter access control. Sounds like everything needed for an over-stretched, sleep-deprived security team to defend the new frontier that is the cloud.</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>BungeeCord And Spigot Servers Venerability</title>
        <author>
            <name>thefourCraft</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/bungeecord-and-spigot-servers-venerability/index.html"/>
        <id>https://blogs.thefourcraft.com/bungeecord-and-spigot-servers-venerability/index.html</id>

        <updated>2022-08-27T00:53:02+03:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                    Introduction Most Minecraft servers today use BungeeCord as their proxy manager. What is BungeeCord? BungeeCord is a useful software written in-house by the team at SpigotMC. It acts as a proxy between the player's client and the connected Minecraft servers. End-users of BungeeCord see no&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                <h2>Introduction</h2>
<p>Most Minecraft servers today use BungeeCord as their proxy manager.<br><strong>What is BungeeCord?</strong><br>BungeeCord is a useful software written in-house by the team at SpigotMC. It acts as a proxy between the player's client and the connected Minecraft servers. End-users of BungeeCord see no difference between it and a normal Minecraft server. - SpigotMC</p>
<h3>The Venerability</h3>
<p>some server owners do a wrong and dangerous setup </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
